Entry Level Software Engineer

A proactive and organized individual with a year of experience in automation development and quality assurance seeking a software development position that utilized skills in the field of Computer Science and Software Engineering. Proven ability to integrate out-of-the-box thinking and problem solving analysis to improve processes, systems, and methodologies. Skilled at team collaboration while working independently in remote environments.

Areas of Expertise

- Software Development
- Database Design
- Development Process
- Agile/SCRUM

- Software Testing
- Extensive Programming
- User Requirements Gathering
- Web Development

- RESTful Services
- Operational Improvements
- Service and Quality Mindset
- Hardware Configuration

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems | San Diego State University, San Diego, CA, 12/2017 **Minor – Computer Science**

Master of Science in Computer Science | San Diego State University, San Diego, CA. Expected completion 2021

<u>Coursework</u>: Data Structure and Algorithms, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Management Systems, Info Systems Analysis and Design, Programming Language, Computer Architecture, Formal Language and Automata, Operating Systems

PROJECTS

Data Management Systems – Designed Database system for School of Pharmacy
Info System Analysis – Group project- Built Drone Delivery system for Pharmacy
Info System Design – Group Project – Designed and built Educational Game for low-income students
TECHNOLOGY PROFICIENCIES

Java, JavaScript, C#, HTML, SQL Server CSS, Oracle PL/SQL, C++, Linux, Git, Cucumber.js

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

AMERICAN SPECIALTY HEALTH, San Diego, CA 1/2019 to present

Associate Software Engineer in Test

Perform system, acceptance, regression, load and functional testing on the software and web applications using both automated and manual testing methods. Validate, verify, communicate and resolve software issues through careful.

- Identified, documented and reported bugs, defect, interoperability flaws within proprietary software applications.
- Design, develop and maintaining API and UI test automation suites for use in development and testing cycles.
- Knowledge of software development lifecycle, testing methodologies, testing tools.
- Working collaboratively with development team and business groups to complete comprehensive testing.

RITZ TOURS, Alhambra, CA, 10/2018 to present

Manual Web Tester

Create and implement viable testing routines with the test plans and mapped them with specific requirements utilizing the tests coverage feature of quality center.

- Executing formal test plans and tracks quality assurance metrics such as defects, defect counts, test results and test status.
- Documents all problems and report to the supervisor. Communicate bugs to the developers.
- Repeated tests on the numerous processes and procedures on internal and externally facing websites.

HOOKIT, Solana Beach, CA 8/2017 to 12/2017

Data Coordinator Internship

Utilized articulate communications in conducting processing, analysis, interpretation, and maintained strong problem-solving abilities to determine appropriate data types.

• Wrote data extraction queries and views for reporting utilizing SQL Server and reported quality assurance and gained practical business experience.

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY, San Diego, CA, 8/2015 to 1/2018

Computer Lab Assistant

Responsible for identifying, analyzing, and resolving technical problems in a professional manner by providing guidance to students and faculty on various software, tools, and applications.

 Assists with system security, installs proper security patching including anti-virus and anti-spam software. Diagnoses, repairs, and maintains various computer devices, network connections, and software. Test hardware to ensure security and develop key processes to enhance the instructional program. Helped and tutored students on math homework activities.